<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on EMCR Brain Science Network Website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on EMCR Brain Science Network Website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Louisa Selvadurai</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-louisa-selvadurai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-louisa-selvadurai/</guid>
      <description>Dr Louisa Selvadurai is a Research Fellow at the School of Psychological Sciences, Monash University, and a psychologist (clinical neuropsychology registrar). Dr Selvadurai’s research focuses characterising and tracking cognition, mood, and behaviour in cerebellar disorders, in particular degenerative ataxias. She has a particular interest in understanding how non-motor features play a role in the day-to-day experience of individuals with these disorders, which are primarily known for their motor symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Annabel Short</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-annabel-short/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-annabel-short/</guid>
      <description>Dr Annabel Short is a Senior Research Fellow at the Telethon Kids Institute. Her research focus is identifying molecular mechanisms promoting vulnerabilities to chronic diseases of the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Elysia Sokolenko</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-elysia-sokolenko/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-elysia-sokolenko/</guid>
      <description>Dr Sokolenko is a research coordinator and lecturer at the University of Adelaide. She has a particular interest in exploring differences in the electrical activity of the brain underlying cognitive impairment in psychiatric disorders. Elysia is currently the local site coordinator for a national trial using transcranial magnetic stimulation in autism. She is also leading the design of a research skills development program in the University of Adelaide’s Bachelor of Medical Studies/Doctor of Medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kristin Barry</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-kristin-barry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-kristin-barry/</guid>
      <description>Dr Kristin Barry is an auditory neuroscientist at the University of Western Australia and Ear Science Institute Australia. Dr Barry’s expertise lies using electrophysiology, behavioural neuroscience, calcium imaging and translational animal models to investigate hearing loss, cognition, tinnitus, and neuronal excitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A/Prof Carolyn Semmler</title>
      <link>/profiles/a-prof-carolyn-semmler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/a-prof-carolyn-semmler/</guid>
      <description>A/Prof. Carolyn Semmler leads the Applied Cognition and Experimental Psychology (ACEP) research group at the University of Adelaide, focusing on the application of theories and models of cognition, judgement and decision-making to legal and medical contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD student profile: Isabella Bower</title>
      <link>/profiles/isabella-bower/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/isabella-bower/</guid>
      <description>Dr Isabella Bower is an emerging leader in environmental cognitive neuroscience. Isabella’s work explores whether we can improve brain functioning and mental health through built environment design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs Outside the Bubble 4</title>
      <link>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-4/</guid>
      <description>The fourth in our popular webinar series, which will be held on Friday, September 2nd 2022, from 1-2pm (Melbourne/Sydney time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Heidi Walkden</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-heidi-waldken/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-heidi-waldken/</guid>
      <description>Dr Walkden’s research identified a new path by which bacteria can move from the nasal cavity to the brain and spinal cord, all within 24 hours.  She has also shown that an injury to the inside of the nasal cavity can increase the bacterial invasion of the brain via the nose-to-brain pathway. Alongside her research, Dr Walkden is also an award-winning science communicator. She has won numerous awards for her oral presentations, scientific photos, and poster prizes. Notably, she reached the grand final of the International Asia-Pacific Three Minute Thesis (3MT) Competition in 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs Outside the Bubble 3</title>
      <link>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-3/</guid>
      <description>The third in our popular webinar series, which will be held on April 8th 2022 from 1-2pm (Melbourne/Sydney time).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A/Prof. Simon Conn</title>
      <link>/profiles/a-prof-simon-conn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/a-prof-simon-conn/</guid>
      <description>A/Prof Simon Conn is an NHMRC Investigator Leadership fellow and runs the Circular RNAs in Cancer Laboratory at Flinders University. His laboratory has a particular strength and focus on RNA splicing in brain cancer and is a proud founding member of the Australian Brain Alliance, EMCR Brain Science Network, which supports interdisciplinary research among Australian EMCRs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Scott Kiel-Chisholm</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-scott-kiel-chisholm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-scott-kiel-chisholm/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Scott Kiel-Chisholm is a researcher at the School of Law, Faculty of Business and Law at Queensland University of Technology (QUT). He is also a researcher in the Datafication and Automation of Human Life Research Program at the Faculty of Law, QUT, focusing on Regulating Life Sciences, Robotics, Neural Interface and the Law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs Outside the Bubble 2</title>
      <link>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble-2/</guid>
      <description>The second in our very popular webinar series, which was held on September 14th from 1-2pm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs Outside the Bubble 1</title>
      <link>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/events/jobs-outside-the-bubble/</guid>
      <description>Recently, many of you joined us in conversation with two outstanding brain scientists who have secured jobs outside of the university sector.  How did they do it? What is it like outside the bubble?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Caladown: A Hugo theme and R package by Danielle Navarro</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Brenton Hordacre</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-brenton-hordacre/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-brenton-hordacre/</guid>
      <description>Dr Brenton Hordacre is an NHMRC early-career research fellow in the Body in Mind Group at the University of South Australia. Excitingly, a major study of Brenton’s is due to wrap up at the end of the year. Launched in 2018, this study attracted much media attention at its debut as it featured the country’s first in-home brain stimulation rehabilitation program for people who have suffered a stroke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2019 Newsletter</title>
      <link>/newsletter/september-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/newsletter/september-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>We are excited to bring you the spring issue of the ABA EMCR Network Newsletter, starting with an update on recent ABA EMCR Network activities. We have teamed up with the EMCR Forum of the Australian Academy of Science to tackle the issue of poor mental health faced by our EMCRs. We bring you our coverage of the ASMR Medical Research Week which took place in June, where brain scientists showcased and dazzled with their research findings all over Australia. We have for you their stories as told by the enthusiastic voices of the researchers themselves. We have the pleasure to introduce to you two interesting researchers: an EMCR who uniquely combines physiotherapy and neuroscience, and a PhD student whose work champions the link between architecture and emotions. Last but not least, we bring you a student&amp;rsquo;s perspective on the 6th Australian EMBL PhD course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A/Prof. Tara Hamilton</title>
      <link>/profiles/a-prof-tara-hamilton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/a-prof-tara-hamilton/</guid>
      <description>Tara Hamilton is an Associate Professor in the School of Engineering at Macquarie University. She currently holds an ARC Discovery Grant which explores auditory perception using neuromorphic systems and an ARC Linkage Grant which focuses on the development of novel music compositions using a deep-net partner. Tara works with leading health, defence, and technology companies and she is focused on developing innovative solutions to real-world problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kristi Griffiths</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-kristi-griffiths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-kristi-griffiths/</guid>
      <description>Dr Kristi Griffiths is a current NHMRC Early Career Research Fellow based at the Brain Dynamics Centre, Westmead Institute for Medical Research and The University of Sydney, investigating brain circuits associated with impaired goal-directed behaviour in ADHD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June 2019 Newsletter</title>
      <link>/newsletter/june-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/newsletter/june-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>In this second edition of our newsletter in 2019, we introduce several EMCRs pushing the boundaries in brain science across Australia. We also have an interesting story of how an internship in industry may help you follow your passion while studying a PhD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 2019 Newsletter</title>
      <link>/newsletter/april-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/newsletter/april-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>In this newsletter we have included a number of profiles of Australian brain EMCRs kicking goals, as well as awesome initiatives getting up and running — like QueersInscience, set up to foster and champion the inclusion of LGBTQIA+ professionals within STEMM organisations. We hope you enjoy being a part of the BSN.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Adam Hamlin</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-adam-hamlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-adam-hamlin/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Adam Hamlin is a neuroscientist working at the University of New England, focusing on pre-clinical studies of anxiety and depression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Ann-Maree Vallence</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-ann-maree-vallence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-ann-maree-vallence/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Ann-Maree Vallence co-leads the Action and Cognition Research Group at Murdoch University, and is a DECRA researcher. She is studying connectivity in the aceing brain and how this relates to the control of movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Deborah Apthorp</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-deborah-apthorp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-deborah-apthorp/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Deborah Apthorp is a senior lecturer at the University of New England. She is a cognitive neuroscientist interested in measuring and tracking neurodegeneratative processes in Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s disease using new, objective measures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Sarah Stephenson, Queers in Science</title>
      <link>/profiles/dr-sarah-stephenson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/profiles/dr-sarah-stephenson/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Sarah Stephenson is a neuroscientist working in the area of brain nevelopment and neuroplasticity. She&amp;rsquo;s also also the co-founder of an organisation called QueersInScience, which aims to foster and champion the inclusion of LGBTQIA+ professionals within STEMM organisations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current EMCR BSN Steering Committee membership</title>
      <link>/steeringcommittee/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/steeringcommittee/</guid>
      <description>Member listing for the current Steering Committee</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links to other EMCR groups</title>
      <link>/emcr-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/emcr-groups/</guid>
      <description>Other brain-related EMCR groups in Australia - brief descriptions and links</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Plan 2023-2026</title>
      <link>/strategicplan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/strategicplan/</guid>
      <description>EMCR Brain Sciences Strategic Plan</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>